LUKE SHAFER

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

614 - 585 - 3382 hello@lukeshafer.com Columbus. Ohio

Links

lukeshafer.com
github.com/lukeshafer

SKILLS

Languages

- TypeScript/JavaScript
- CSS & preprocessors
- Python
- HTML

Libraries & Frameworks

- React
- · Node.is
- WordPress
- Svelte/SvelteKit
- Strapi
- Astro

Practices

- Accessibility
- · Semantic HTML
- Componentization
- · Scalable Design

Soft Skills

- Project management
- Team communication
- · Customer service

PROFILE

Hi! I'm a web developer with over 5 years of professional experience, focused on accessible, modern, and concise design. I'm experienced in modern frontend web technologies, including React and Svelte, and can quickly learn any stack or technology introduced to me.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Columbus, Ohio | Mar 2022 - Present

- · Built 4 full client websites, 2 Discord bots, and a game in under 6 months
- Svelte, Node.js, React, Astro, Colyseus, Strapi CMS, WordPress

Implementation Specialist, TrueCommerce

Columbus, OH | Jan 2021 - Aug 2022

- Led over 100 implementation projects and cases to completion
- · Partnered with customers to build business-driven solutions
- XML, XPath, ODLF, Microsoft Dynamics, ERP integration, NetSuite

Online Coding Instructor, CodeWizardsHQ

Remote | Sept 2020 - Feb 2021

- Taught 5 simultaneous 12-week courses to students with no prior experience
- Python, Scratch, JavaScript

PROJECTS

Fridge Magnets

fridge.lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/fridgemagnets

- Online party/word game, based on the card game Ransom Notes
- Colyseus.io, TypeScript, SvelteKit, Node.JS

Personal Portfolio

lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/lukeshafer.com

- · Statically generated site using SvelteKit
- · Scored 100 in Lighthouse Performance and SEO
- SvelteKit, TypeScript, Vercel

EDUCATION

Bachelor's, Computer Science, 2019

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio

